Ping house
坪屋
jia Ping.
jia Ping.
Miss Zuo, you have come.
左小姐，你来了。
You guys...
你们...
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Nona Zuo,
Nona Zuo,
You don't know anything about us.
你对我们一无所知。
Your boyfriend is Chen Jia Ping
你男朋友是陈家平
Its true identity is the Communist Party
它的真实身份是共产党
Impossible
不可能的
haphazard!
偶然！
Ping Family Home
平家
let me go!
让我走！
Here.
这里。
Jia Ping
Jia Ping
two punctures
两次刺穿
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
You hit a girl. You...
你打了一个女孩。你...
Jia Ping
Jia Ping
It's none of your business here.
这里不关你的事。
Do not move.
不要动。
Jia Ping
Jia Ping
chen Jia Ping
chen Jia Ping
if you confess
如果你承认
we guarantee we will not make it difficult for you.
我们保证不会为您制造困难。
You see Miss Zuo has come,
你看左小姐来了，
don't let him worry.
别让他担心。
Jia Ping
Jia Ping
let him go!
放了他！
chen Jia Ping
chen Jia Ping
you even lied to me
你甚至对我撒谎
quickly admit your mistakes.
赶紧承认你的错误。
Tuan Fang.
Tuan Fang.
Come here a little.
过来一点吧。
Even closer.
更近了。
What do you want to do?
你想让我做什么？
Chen Jia Ping
Chen Jia Ping
do you admit it or not?
你承认还是不承认？
Luo Guanqun,
Luo Guanqun,
aren't you usually brothers?
你们平时不是兄弟吗？
At such an important moment, why don't you help him?
这么重要的时刻，你为什么不帮帮他呢？
Mata-mata PKT
玛塔玛塔 PKT
who can help him?
谁能帮助他？
Ping house
坪屋
Ping family
平家
chen Jia Ping
chen Jia Ping
if he does not plead guilty, he will lose his life
如果他不认罪，他就会失去生命
he admitted.
他承认。
let me go!
让我走！
Jia Ping, Jia Ping
Jia Ping, Jia Ping
pleaded guilty
认罪
then say it.
然后说出来。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Jia Ping
Jia Ping
since when did you join the CCP?
你什么时候加入共产党的？
what is your hidden mission?
你的隐藏任务是什么？
Say it.
说吧。
Jia Ping
Jia Ping
I do admit guilt, Captain Zhao
赵队长我认罪了
but didn't say I was Plum Blossom Four
但没说我是梅花四
what mistake do you admit?
你承认什么错误？
I made a mistake.
我犯了一个错误。
What's that?
那是什么？
Jia Ping
Jia Ping
I had made a very important mistake
我犯了一个非常重要的错误
what does it mean?
这是什么意思？
Ketua Zhao.
Ketua Zhao.
All of these
所有这些
is a true fighter at the foot of the mountain.
是山脚下真正的战士。
Joke with us.
跟我们开玩笑。
What are you saying?
你在说什么？
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Unfortunately he has died.
不幸的是他已经死了。
Ketua Zhao!
Ketua Zhao!
He is cunning.
他很狡猾。
How can it be easily beaten by people?
怎么可能轻易被人打败呢？
Tuan Fang
Tuan Fang
You are by no means a person who surrenders to the CCP
你绝不是一个向中共投降的人
now I have to call you
现在我必须打电话给你
commander of soldiers at the foot of the mountain.
山下的士兵统帅。
Turns out he was.
事实证明他是。
Is a true fighter at the foot of the mountain.
是山脚下真正的战士。
You're too much of a joke
你开得太大了
chen Jia Ping
chen Jia Ping
how do you know
你怎么知道
My identity?
我的身份？
Crown Princess
太子妃
are you wearing Fang Hongnan's clothes?
你穿的是方洪南的衣服吗？
I noticed this cuff
我注意到了这个手镯
there are obvious friction marks.
有明显的摩擦痕迹。
It means
它的意思是
Fang Hongnan often uses his left hand.
方洪南经常使用左手。
However, you were smoking earlier,
然而，你早些时候吸烟，
use the right hand.
使用右手。
So I decided
所以我决定
You're a regular right hand man
你是一个普通的得力助手
if
如果
fang Hongnan wearing someone else's clothes?
方宏南穿了别人的衣服？
Of course.
当然。
Is what you said the least bit wrong?
你说的有一点点错误吗？
But I still noticed one detail.
但我还是注意到了一个细节。
Didn't your leg hurt?
你的腿没受伤吗？
I found the other thumb and toes
我找到了另一个拇指和脚趾
the gap in the middle was very wide.
中间的差距非常大。
This is a burn
这是烧伤
Japanese people often wear clogs
日本人经常穿木屐
So
所以
you...
你...
Bukan Fang Hongnan.
Bukan Fang Hongnan.
I bet you're a great fighter from the foot of the mountain.
我敢打赌，你一定是一位来自山脚下的伟大战士。
Great.
伟大的。
Unexpected
意外
your business
你的事
there's still this thing.
还有这个东西
Very wise and brave,
非常聪明又勇敢，
commander of soldiers at the foot of the mountain.
山下的士兵统帅。
Thank goodness you're still alive.
谢天谢地你还活着。
Chen Jia Ping
Chen Jia Ping
he just
他只是
a little ingenuity
一点点聪明才智
does not erase the error
不会消除错误
I feel
我觉得
continue the interrogation.
继续审讯。
Attract.
吸引。
The tactics that Kazuo made under the mountain this time
这次一雄在山下制定的战术
very interesting.
很有意思。
Not only destroys the murderous conspiracy
不仅摧毁了杀机阴谋
also made Chen Jia Ping
也成就了陈家平
get training.
接受培训。
But this time he passed this test.
但这一次他通过了这次考验。
In my opinion, this...
在我看来，这...
It should have ended.
本来就该结束了。
Can't end.
无法结束。
The problem is not finished yet,
问题还没完，
how can it be finished so easily?
怎么可能这么容易就完成了呢？
Do you all know?
你们都知道吗？
Luo Guan Qun and Chen Jia Ping's relationship was very close
罗冠群与陈家平关系十分密切
he is protecting his shortcomings.
他在保护自己的缺点。
I protect,
我保护，
I only think about the public interest.
我只考虑公共利益。
Wh... what did you say just now?
呃……你刚才说什么？
For the good of China-Japan,
为了中日两国的利益，
what if it spreads?
如果传播怎么办？
Aren't the top officials from the military headquarters also unwilling?
军部高层不也不愿意吗？
True, or not?
是真是假？
Won't be angry.
不会生气。
As long as we interrogate him,
只要我们审问他
won't be unhappy.
不会不高兴。
You believe me.
你相信我。
The great prince of the mountains.
伟大的山王子。
Your opinion is
你的意见是
Chen Jia Ping was indeed suspected
陈家平确实被怀疑
but we have no proof
但我们没有证据
we cannot slander
我们不能诽谤
talented people who are loyal to the Japanese nation.
忠于日本民族的人才。
According to me,
据我说，
talented people like this
像这样的人才
I feel
我觉得
we have to give
我们必须给予
trusted and reused.
值得信赖并重用。
Tuan Luo,
Tuan Luo,
Correct.
正确的。
Let him go.
放了他。
Good.
好的。
Ketua Zhao.
Ketua Zhao.
Can't let go of people
放不下人
case 4 Plum Blossoms.
案例4 梅花。
Murder at the train station
火车站谋杀案
I will give you one more month
我再给你一个月的时间
if you still can't solve the case
如果你仍然无法破案
I'll let you try it too.
我也让你试试。
Kudaku.
库达库。
What if it's just me?
如果只有我一个人怎么办？
A bunch of traitors.
一群叛徒。
Cruel, poisonous, inhumane.
残忍、有毒、无人性。
Not.
不是。
Don't take me if you scold them.
如果你骂他们，别带我去。
I will take you.
我会带你。
Look at you,
看着你，
as a traitor,
作为一个叛徒，
What? Not arrested?
什么？没有被捕？
Punished and interrogated.
受到惩罚和审讯。
To death, is it worth it to you?
死，对你来说值得吗？
Lower your voice.
降低你的声音。
You still think I don't have enough problems?
你还觉得我的问题还不够多吗？
Jia Ping
Jia Ping
what wind brought you here
是什么风把你吹到这里来的
are you okay?
你还好吗？
Go, go.
走吧，走吧。
It is okay now.
现在没事了。
Very pleasant.
非常愉快。
Next time, Manager Luo also try.
下次，罗经理也试试。
You see, just get angry at me.
你看，就对我生气吧。
Guoguo.
Guoguo.
If it weren't for Manager Luo,
要不是罗经理，
Today specially said a few words to me.
今天特地跟我说了几句话。
Zhao An is still not over.
赵安还没完。
Then we should thank him.
那我们就应该感谢他。
Of course.
当然。
Enough already.
已经足够。
Nona Zuo,
Nona Zuo,
Jia Ping and I talked about work matters.
我和贾平聊了工作上的事情。
Not angry?
不生气？
Do not be angry.
别生气。
In your heart you are just like your girlfriend.
在你心里你就像你的女朋友一样。
It's my fault I didn't help you,
是我的错，没能帮你
and mad at me?
还生我的气吗？
This is all you can see,
这就是你能看到的全部
I really do not know
我真的不知道
fang Hongnan is a person
方宏南是一个人
how could you not know?
你怎么会不知道呢？
I swear.
我发誓。
Just think about it.
考虑一下。
Zhao An is a person from Mu Village,
赵安是木村人，
can you tell me about their conspiracy?
你能告诉我他们的阴谋吗？
We are in the same boat.
我们在同一条船上。
On the same ship?
在同一艘船上？
Then you put poison in me huh?
那你给我下了毒啊？
I don't hold a grudge against you.
我对你没有怨恨。
When Kimura was still around,
当木村还在的时候，
I can only obey him.
我只能服从他。
Actually what I was thinking about was how to save you.
其实我想的是如何拯救你。
I asked you Luo
我问你罗
are you still suspicious now?
你现在还怀疑吗？
Am I the Plum Blossom?
我是梅花吗？
Are you here to test me?
你是来考验我的吗？
You say it yourself.
你自己说吧。
How could I suspect you?
我怎么会怀疑你呢？
Good.
好的。
I'll tell you one piece of information,
我告诉你一个信息，
You will know whether I doubt you or not.
你就会知道我是否怀疑你。
I don't want to hear me.
我不想听我说。
After Fang Hongnan was poisoned,
方洪南中毒后，
The foot of the mountain is willing to sacrifice to save him,
山下愿意牺牲来救他，
tell subordinates,
告诉下属，
he mastered a
他掌握了一个
name list.
名单。
What name list?
什么名单？
List of hidden names in PKT
PKT 中的隐藏名称列表
now in the French concession
现在在法租界
in the Lumiere bank vault
在卢米埃银行金库里
I understand.
我明白。
You want to ask me
你想问我
return this list of names?
返回这个名单？
Zhao An will immediately go get it.
赵安立即去拿。
I hope,
我希望，
before Zhao An got it,
在赵安拿到之前，
you get it first,
你先得到它，
then, catch one more time
然后，再抓一次
those on this name list.
名单上的人。
You think Zhao An is stupid?
你以为赵安傻吗？
We arrest all these CCPs
我们把这些CCP全部抓起来
arrest all CCPs like this.
中共都这样抓起来。
Does Zhao An suspect that we have taken the name list?
赵安是不是怀疑我们拿走了名单？
He will report to Kimura.
他将向木村汇报。
Will you be in trouble?
你会遇到麻烦吗？
I've thought about this.
我已经考虑过这个问题。
I'll make a fake report,
我会做一个假报告
explain what we do
解释我们做什么
clear the relationship with this list of fake names.
澄清与这份假名单的关系。
Later we will serve,
稍后我们将服务，
Zhao An sentenced him.
赵安判了他一句。
All of this will be perfect.
这一切都将是完美的。
Great too Luo
罗也太厉害了
not careless.
不粗心。
So
所以
how could I suspect that you are Plum Blossom?
我怎么会怀疑你是梅花呢？
If not, can I tell you this?
如果没有，我可以告诉你这个吗？
Good.
好的。
For now I believe you.
现在我相信你。
I'm really worried about you.
我真的很担心你。
Go away.
离开。
Sister.
姐姐。
According to me,
据我说，
Plum Blossom Four's case
梅花四的案例
based on our abilities
基于我们的能力
of course it won't work.
当然行不通。
But just calm down
但冷静一下
we still think the old way
我们仍然以旧方式思考
make some moves
采取一些行动
beat drums and gongs.
敲锣打鼓。
This can be said to be a comparison.
这可以说是一个比较。
What I'm afraid of isn't Plum Blossoms,
我怕的不是梅花，
So what are you worried about?
那么你担心什么？
Chen Jia Ping
Chen Jia Ping
chen Jia Ping
chen Jia Ping
Luo Guanqun is now a coward
罗冠群现在是个胆小鬼
still a green turtle.
依然是绿海龟。
Kau kira Luo Guan Qun
Kau kira Luo Guan Qun
willing to be this display?
愿意成为这个显示器吗？
He just hides behind
他只是躲在后面
he wanted to find a chance to rise again.
他想寻找重新崛起的机会。
At first I thought
起初我以为
there was no one who could help him
没有人可以帮助他
Chen Jia Ping didn't think of it
陈家平没想到
I used to underestimate him
我曾经低估他
Correct.
正确的。
He could even discern the disguise of the officers at the foot of the mountain.
他甚至能够辨别出山下那些军官的伪装。
His abilities are extraordinary
他的能力非凡
fold two formations in a row
连续折叠两个阵型
Oh yes
哦是的
You recently helped me follow someone,
你最近帮我关注了某人，
Who
WHO
French concession
法租界
governor of Lumiere bank
卢米埃尔银行行长
think of a way
想办法
to look for weaknesses.
寻找弱点。
It was unexpected that the mountain warriors were so cunning.
没想到山里的武士竟然如此狡猾。
We have all been deceived.
我们都被欺骗了。
The secret letter must still be in his hands,
那封密信一定还在他手里，
but there was no chance to intervene again.
但已经没有机会再干预了。
How about this?
这个怎么样？
Leave Shanghai immediately.
立即离开上海。
Can't.
不能。
In that case,
在这种情况下，
Xiao Hu.
Xiao Hu.
Da Xuan.
Da Xuan.
Everything was sacrificed in vain.
一切都白白牺牲了。
Take it.
拿去。
Thank You.
谢谢。
Sir, what would you like to order?
先生，您想点什么？
Two little white clouds,
两朵小白云，
I really didn't expect so many accidents to happen.
实在没想到会发生这么多事故。
Even though Fang Hongnan is dead,
方洪南虽然死了，
but if this list of names is revealed,
但如果这份名单被公开的话
then it would be more troublesome than Fang Hongnan.
那可就比方洪南还麻烦了。
Do you have a way to reclaim this name list?
你有办法收回这个名单吗？
I think of a way.
我想到一个办法。
No, think of a way.
不行，得想想办法。
This list of names is related
这份名单是相关的
life and death of organizations in Shanghai.
上海组织的生与死。
Correct.
正确的。
I promise I will complete the task.
我保证我会完成任务。
Left twin peach.
左双桃。
Have you ever suspected anything?
你有没有怀疑过什么？
It shouldn't be yet.
应该还没有。
Have you ever suspected him?
你曾经怀疑过他吗？
I never suspected
我从来没有怀疑过
but after I investigated,
但我调查之后，
looks like him
看起来像他
nothing to do with
与 无关
with the case of killing Mount Xia warriors.
以杀夏山武士为例。
So you plan
所以你计划
how to manage your relationship with him?
如何处理你和他的关系？
Maintain a relationship first.
先维持关系。
This way, it's good for me
这样对我来说有好处
nor for him
也不适合他
still a protection.
还是一种保护。
After that, just look for opportunities
之后就只是寻找机会
to end this relationship.
来结束这段关系。
The ending you mean is
你说的结局是
end of publication
出版结束
or the end of your heart?
还是你心的尽头？
Does my heart want it to end?
我的心想要结束吗？
Is this really important?
这真的很重要吗？
Very important.
很重要。
I...
我...
In my heart I also want it to end.
我心里也希望这一切能够结束。
Good.
好的。
Before this
在这之前
you must protect your identity,
您必须保护您的身份，
Don't let the Left Peach suspect you in the slightest.
别让左桃对你有丝毫怀疑。
Understand.
理解。
Oh yeah, a long way to go.
哦，是的，还有很长的路要走。
Do you know the Shan Project?
你知道掸邦计划吗？
Shan Project?
山项目？
It could be said that I can go home early.
可以说可以早点回家了。
Correct.
正确的。
This girl...
这个女孩...
Been waiting here for half a month, right?
已经在这里等了半个月了吧？
True, or not?
是真是假？
It's dead, right?
它死了，对吧？
Don't be careless, lower your voice.
别大意，放低声音。
Nona,
诺娜，
we're done working.
我们工作结束了。
Go away.
离开。
Nona,
诺娜，
the weather is cold.
天气很冷。
Drink warm water to avoid catching a cold.
喝温水，避免感冒。
Thank You.
谢谢。
There are some fates.
有一些命运。
Don't mind too much if you miss it.
如果你错过了也不要太在意。
Even though I don't know what happened to you,...
虽然我不知道你发生了什么事，...
But I suggest you keep an open mind.
但我建议你保持开放的心态。
You care so much about that person,
你那么在乎那个人，
people may not know,
人们可能不知道，
and don't care.
并不在乎。
According to you?
照你说的？
You're still very young
你还很年轻
the road ahead is still long.
前面的路还很长。
The ending you mean is
你说的结局是
end of disclosure
披露结束
or the end of the heart
或心的尽头
the heart also wants it to end.
心也希望它结束​​。
Who told you to look?
谁叫你看的？
When are you coming here?
你什么时候来这里？
Why write all this?
为什么要写这一切？
I write for myself.
我为自己写作。
I am happy.
我很开心。
This is what you want
这就是你想要的
youth?
青年？
I know
我知道
you've suffered a lot.
你受了很多苦。
I'll write the rest tonight.
今晚我会写剩下的。
If there's nothing else, you can just go home first.
如果没有别的事情的话，你就先回家吧。
Good.
好的。
I'll pick it up again tomorrow.
明天我再去取。
There is a scale,
有一个尺度，
is clearly known,
清楚地知道，
This traitor was named Fang Hongnan.
这个叛徒名叫方洪南。
Now we have succeeded in eradicating the traitors.
现在我们已经成功铲除叛徒了。
Fang Hongnan.
Fang Hongnan.
This person is not simple.
这个人不简单。
Plum Blossom Si received the news,
梅花司收到消息，
Fang Hongnan mastered a document
方洪南掌握了一份文件
list the names of several team members
列出几名团队成员的姓名
di Shanghai.
di Shanghai.
Looks like Fang Hongnan
Looks like Fang Hongnan
had already prepared it for himself.
早就给自己准备好了。
Negotiate with powerful enemies
与强大的敌人谈判
now where is this list?
现在这个列表在哪里？
Lumiere Bank in the French Concession
法租界的卢米埃尔银行
even if they are Japanese
即使他们是日本人
also will not dare to do anything in the French concession
也不敢在法租界做什么
Correct
正确的
so the name list has not been leaked.
所以名单并没有被泄露。
But time is pressing.
但时间紧迫。
I've told Meihua Si to think of everything
我已经告诉司美华凡事都要考虑清楚
to reclaim that list of names
收回那份名单
reclaim the name list
收回名单
plum blossom four.
梅花四。
Are you sure?
你确定吗？
The four plum blossoms fell asleep for a very long time.
四朵梅花睡了很长时间。
But in my judgment,
但根据我的判断，
I believe him.
我相信他。
Now can only depend on him.
现在只能靠他了。
If an accident occurs,
如果发生意外，
we are disbanded.
我们解散了。
Meet opposite the customs building
在海关大楼对面集合
meet opposite the customs building.
在海关大楼对面集合。
8 am three days in a row
连续三天早上8点
See you.
再见。
You're okay
你还好
shot
射击
the bullet penetrated from the side of the waist
子弹从腰部侧面贯穿
not injured, will not die.
不受伤，就不会死。
Just live
只是活着
we are really unlucky.
我们真的很不幸。
Coincidentally met spy Han Xiao at the train station.
巧合的是在火车站遇见了间谍韩萧。
We're not unlucky
我们并不不幸
but we are trapped
但我们被困住了
the poisoned person is not a soldier at the foot of the mountain.
中毒者不是山下的士兵。
The secret letter was completely lost.
那封密信完全丢失了。
What should we do?
我们应该做什么？
I know where.
我知道在哪里。
Where?
在哪里？
When I saw in the morgue
当我在太平间看到
corpse under a fake mountain
假山下的尸体
I found a button on his shirt.
我在他的衬衫上发现了一颗纽扣。
Different from other buttons.
与其他按钮不同。
At that time I felt very strange,
当时我就觉得很奇怪，
then I just remembered
然后我才想起来
that day in the small forest near the business shop
那天在商铺附近的小森林里
under the mountain,
山下，
buttons on his shirt
他衬衫上的纽扣
one button is different from another
一个按钮与另一个按钮不同
do you understand?
你明白吗？
They exchanged studs.
他们交换了螺柱。
So I conclude
所以我得出结论
the studs are very important to the mountain.
螺柱对于山峰来说非常重要。
It doesn't matter what clothes he changes into,
不管他换什么衣服
he will take her everywhere
他会带她去任何地方
however, now we just understand,
然而，现在我们才明白，
is it too late?
是不是太晚了？
there is one place
有一个地方
maybe you can get information about the foot of the mountain.
也许你可以获得有关山脚的信息。
I can try it.
我可以尝试一下。
Are you afraid?
你害怕吗？
Now the whole organization
现在整个组织
was collecting money and leaving the back way.
正在收钱，然后离开后路。
Fighting Japan and saving the country became nonsense.
抗日救国都成了无稽之谈。
Only you are so serious.
只有你这么认真。
I'll think of a way.
我会想办法。
You quickly leave Shanghai.
你很快就离开上海了。
Good morning.
早上好。
Xiu Cai asked you
Xiu Cai asked you
in this one year
在这一年里
did section chief Chen ever accept
陈科长接受过吗
letter from Wuhan?
武汉来信？
There should be.
应该有。
You're just a gatekeeper,
你只是一个看门人
all day looking at this is useless.
整天看这个没啥用。
Want to be emperor?
想当皇帝吗？
Look at it.
看它。
For you.
为你。
Have you received any letters from Wuhan?
你有收到来自武汉的来信吗？
Who?
WHO？
Department head Chen takes care of marketing and general affairs
陈部长分管市场及综合事务
there is always money and goods
总是有金钱和物品
from his hand
从他手中
He also has more letters than anyone else.
他的信件也比任何人都多。
Letter from Wuhan?
武汉来信？
There must be.
必须有。
Then you help me look for it.
那你帮我找找吧。
Try searching.
尝试搜索。
Nona Zuo.
Nona Zuo.
Good morning.
早上好。
You can't go in.
你不能进去。
Really sorry
真对不起
Today
今天
I can't let you in again.
我不能再让你进来了。
Yesterday
昨天
there's something special.
有一些特别的东西。
Usually at our place
一般都是在我们家
casual people cannot enter.
普通人不能进入。
On what basis?
依据什么？
This is the rule,
这就是规则，
what are the rules?
规则是什么？
Slandering the Ping Family.
诽谤平家。
Hurting our family.
伤害了我们的家人。
I can't change the medicine
我无法换药
Want to ask Manager Luo to appraise it.
想请罗经理鉴定一下。
I'm going to complain to him, believe it or not?
我要去投诉他，信不信？
Qian Xiu Cai
Qian Xiu Cai
Miss Zuo is not an outsider.
左小姐并不是外人。
Send Miss Zuo up,
送左小姐上来，
I will vouch for Miss Zuo.
我为左小姐担保。
In that case...
在这种情况下...
Okay.
好的。
Do not be too long.
不要太长。
Fine, I understand. You just go busy.
好吧，我明白了。你就去忙吧。
Until found.
直到被发现。
Thank You.
谢谢。
Do not hesitate.
不要犹豫。
Big horse.
大马。
Spoon.
勺子。
Silakan, Nona Zuo.
Silakan, Nona Zuo.
This side.
这边。
You're still here
你还在这里
Section Chief Chen, I have an urgent matter
陈科长，我有急事
you sign immediately
你立即签字
I told you 2 stabs
我告诉过你2刺
what you filled in is not correct.
您填写的内容不正确。
I can't sign it.
我无法签名。
Why isn't it true
为什么这不是真的
now entered the French concession
现已进入法租界
everything will be reported to the military police station
一切都会报告军警派出所
Commander of the Military Police Soldiers?
宪兵部队司令？
Why have I never heard?
为什么我从来没有听说过？
I'm guessing Captain Zhao never told you guys.
我猜赵队长从来没有告诉过你们。
I'll tell you.
我会告诉你。
Work in our field
在我们的领域工作
have to think a lot
必须想很多
read more newspapers,
多看报纸，
know more about the current situation, right?
对现在的情况比较了解吧？
Now when?
现在，当？
Now that's Japanese
现在是日语了
currently negotiating with America
目前正在与美国谈判
in a tense situation like this,
在这样紧张的情况下，
the slightest bit of chaos that occurs,
发生一点点的混乱，
will have an impact on the international situation
将对国际局势产生影响
anyway, think about it
不管怎样，想想看
now the Japanese entered the French concession
现在日本人进入了法租界
You also have to be very careful
你也必须非常小心
how can we enter at will?
怎么可以随意进入呢？
How can it let us in at will?
怎么可以随意放我们进去呢？
Just walk out?
就出去走走吗？
Right?
正确的？
Chief Chen, help me think of a way
陈局长，帮我想想办法吧
let's make it like this
让我们把它变成这样
you take this
你拿这个
then take it home to Captain Zhao.
然后带回家给赵队长。
What time do you come in?
你什么时间进来？
What time does it come out?
几点出来啊？
Write where you go.
写下你去的地方。
Then bring it here, then I'll sign it.
然后把它带到这里，然后我签字。
Otherwise, I can't sign it.
不然我没法签字。
brother
兄弟
I'm really not the one looking for trouble with you.
我真的不是找你麻烦的人。
Even though I signed it,
虽然是我签的，
You take this to Military Police Headquarters.
你把这个带到宪兵总部。
The Japanese didn't sign it either.
日本人也没有签字。
True, or not?
是真是假？
Hurry up.
赶快。
Very troublesome.
很麻烦。
Of course.
当然。
I'm waiting for you, go quickly.
我在等你，快点走吧。
It seems like,
这好像是，
Zhao An has succeeded
赵安成功了
road to Lumiere Bank.
通往卢米埃银行的路。
He went to the French concession
他去了法租界
definitely for the list of names that Fang Hongnan said.
肯定是为了方洪南所说的名单。
If you can't use this opportunity to reclaim the name list,
如果你不能利用这个机会夺回名单，
I'm afraid there won't be another chance
恐怕不会再有机会了
make a chicken feather as an arrow
把鸡毛做成箭头
Correct.
正确的。
To bribe Director Pierre
贿赂导演皮埃尔
which is in the Lumiere bank
在卢米埃尔银行
we've spent so much money
我们花了这么多钱
in the end, don't let this boy
最后，不要让这个男孩
ruin our relationship.
破坏我们的关系。
It's not a question of money at all.
这根本不是钱的问题。
This is information
这是信息
It is very difficult to get information from the CCP
从中共获取信息非常困难
sister
姐姐
I saw soldiers at the foot of the mountain just like that.
我看到山下的士兵就是这样。
Take all his plans into account.
把他的所有计划都考虑在内。
In the end, the CCP traitor was poisoned to death.
最终，中共汉奸被毒死。
What can you understand?
你能明白什么？
Don't underestimate the mountain warriors
不要低估山地战士
he colluded with high-ranking military officials
他与军方高级官员勾结
selling tobacco and land in this region
在该地区出售烟草和土地
very profitable.
非常有利可图。
We must learn from it.
我们必须从中吸取教训。
Nona Zuo,
Nona Zuo,
why are you here?
你为什么在这？
I came to look for Chen Jia Ping
我是来找陈家平的
Chen Jia Ping's office was on the second floor
陈家平的办公室在二楼
why did you come to the 3rd floor?
你为什么来到三楼？
I know.
我知道。
I thought I didn't find it in the toilet.
我以为我在厕所里没有找到它。
Why are toilets here so hard to find?
为什么这里的厕所这么难找？
In our place there are many men,
在我们这里有很多男人，
Women's toilets are only available on the fourth floor.
女厕所仅在四楼设有。
Good.
好的。
Who
WHO
did something happen?
发生了什么事吗？
The letter I wrote is lost.
我写的信丢了。
The letter disappeared.
那封信消失了。
Where did you put it?
你把它放在哪里了？
In the bag
在包里
a total of 12 letters.
总共12个字母。
Where not to meet?
哪里不可以见面？
This is your only place?
这是你唯一的地方吗？
Why did you bring a letter to our place?
你为什么带信到我们这里来？
This is for you.
这是给您的。
Didn't I say I'd go get it?
我不是说我要去拿吗？
And also,
并且，
Why do you want to come to Shangxing?
为什么要来上兴？
Didn't I want to change your bandage?
我不是想给你换绷带吗？
I'll give it to you at the same time.
我同时给你。
Do you know my place?
你知道我的位置吗？
beyond all eyes and ears.
超出所有人的眼睛和耳朵。
Think carefully.
仔细想想。
Is it possible that the letter got lost along the way?
有没有可能这封信在途中丢失了？
Impossible.
不可能的。
When I entered, I still saw it.
当我进去的时候，我仍然看到了它。
That time is still there.
那个时光依然存在。
Most likely
最有可能的
looks like the people here
看起来像这里的人
who stole your letter.
谁偷了你的信。
Who can steal letters?
谁能偷信？
Think carefully
仔细想想
Is there anyone
有没有人
who approached you?
谁接近你了？
Upon entry
入境时
qian Xiu blocked me from entering.
钱修阻止我进去。
Then Da Ma Shao helped me say
然后大马少帮我说
he just let me in.
他就让我进去了。
Big spoon.
大勺子。
You came in with the Spoon Horse?
你是带着勺子马进来的吗？
True, but there is distance between us.
确实如此，但我们之间还是有距离的。
Supposedly, Horse Spoon stole your letter.
据说是马勺偷了你的信。
He used to be a thief.
他曾经是一个小偷。
As long as you come in,
只要你进来，
enough for him to act.
足够他行动了。
Additionally, people are suspicious of letters
此外，人们对信件表示怀疑
who suspected the letter was also him.
怀疑这封信也是他本人。
So how?
又怎样？
Don't make a fuss yet.
暂时先别大惊小怪。
Let me think.
让我想想。
Has the date on the letter been written?
信上有写日期吗？
According to last year's date,
根据去年的日期，
what about the ink, has it been processed?
墨水怎么样，经过处理了吗？
Like you said
像你说的
light a match and grill it.
点燃火柴并烧烤它。
Is the letter folded?
信被折叠了吗？
Didn't you fold in half?
你不是对折了吗？
I also folded the rest.
剩下的我也折叠起来。
There are still some.
还有一些。
I accidentally folded several times
不小心折叠了好几次
the effect of repeated reading.
反复阅读的效果。
Plus the letter paper
再加上信纸
is paper bought at the second-hand market.
是在二手市场买的纸。
Even though there are no envelopes or postal stamps,
尽管没有信封或邮票，
but in a short time
但在很短的时间内
they won't suspect anything either.
他们也不会怀疑任何事情。
Is there no longer a problem now?
现在不再有问题了吗？
There is still one thing that is most important
还有一件事是最重要的
these letters were written by you
这些信是你写的
why is it still in your hands?
为什么它还在你手里？
There is only one explanation.
只有一种解释。
These letters
这些字母
do you want to go back yourself?
你想自己回去吗？
But why did I do that?
但我为什么要这么做呢？
Why do that?
为什么要这么做？
We both argue.
我们都争论。
You want to break up with me?
你想和我分手吗？
To take back all these love letters.
夺回所有这些情书。
Why fight?
为什么要打架？
Lu Fang
Lu Fang
earlier when you came to my office
早些时候你来我办公室的时候
no one should see
没有人应该看到
I made an appointment with Lu Fang at nine o'clock
我和吕方约了九点钟
regarding this month's bill
关于本月的账单
you pretend you never came here
你假装你从未来过这里
when you came to look for me, I wasn't there
你来找我的时候我不在
You've asked everyone, where am I?
你问过所有人，我在哪里？
Finally found me in the meeting room.
终于在会议室找到了我。
Then, I found it.
然后，我找到了。
Correct.
正确的。
You today originally wanted to
你今天本来想
talk nicely with me.
跟我好好说话。
Give me another chance.
再给我一次机会。
But unexpectedly,
但没想到的是，
caught in the act
当场被捕
I'm going there now
我现在就去那儿
5 more minutes
还有5分钟
You go to the finance room look for me.
你去财务室找我吧。
Not that you said
不是你说的
Want to get my autograph?
想得到我的签名吗？
When are you coming here?
你什么时候来这里？
Later I will go look for you.
稍后我会去找你。
Wait.
等待。
Enter.
进入。
Manager Luo,
Manager Luo,
guess what I got?
猜猜我得到了什么？
What?
什么？
The letter written by the left Shuang Tao to Chen Jiaping a year ago
左双涛一年前写给陈家平的信
however, I feel
然而，我觉得
faked.
伪造的。
Faked?
伪造的？
Do you still remember?
你还记得吗？
Yesterday I went to Yu's residence,
昨天我去了余家，
akhirnya bibi Zuo Shuang Tao
akhirnya bibi Zuo Shuang Tao
said something very suspicious.
说了一些很可疑的话。
Go away.
离开。
Shuang Tao, every letter mentions you
双涛，每封信都提到你
it's just that, in the past few years,
只是，在过去的几年里，
this past year I rarely brought it up.
去年我很少提起这件事。
I think it's both of you
我认为是你们两个
place, place
地方，地方
Look at my mouth.
看看我的嘴。
These letters,
这些信，
I stole from Shuang Tao's left bag.
我偷了双桃左边的包。
Just think about it.
考虑一下。
This is a letter from the left twin to Chen Jiaping.
这是左双胞胎写给陈家平的一封信。
So why is it in the left peach double bag?
那么为什么会在左桃双包里呢？
It must be because yesterday they realized
一定是因为昨天他们意识到
I suspect them
我怀疑他们
so I forged these letters.
所以我伪造了这些信。
So what you mean is
所以你的意思是
in this one year
在这一年里
no correspondence at all.
根本没有信件往来。
Maybe they have broken up
也许他们已经分手了
then meet at the train station
然后在火车站集合
also coincidental.
也很巧合。
Correct.
正确的。
This also shows that they really have something in their hearts.
这也说明，他们心里确实有事。
Until we fake all this
直到我们伪造这一切
what about the letter?
那封信呢？
Not.
不是。
I obviously put it in my bag.
我明明把它放进包里的。
Just think about it.
考虑一下。
I stole the Left Twin's letter,
我偷了左双胞胎的信
then I went back to the office,
然后我就回到办公室
just a glance, no problem.
只要看一眼，没问题。
I was afraid of being seen by other people, so I used this file bag.
我怕被别人看到，所以就用了这个文件袋。
So, I came looking for you.
于是，我就来找你了。
So,
所以，
in the middle I went to the toilet.
中间我去了趟厕所。
Then I entered the toilet.
然后我进了厕所。
Want to defecate,
想排便，
impractical, then I...
不切实际，那我...
Placed on top of the toilet.
放置在马桶顶部。
In this toilet partition.
在这个厕所隔断里。
Already changed.
已经变了。
Impossible.
不可能的。
When I entered, there was no one.
我进去的时候，没有人。
Large horse spoon.
大马勺。
You will be of service.
您将竭诚为您服务。
Now let their shit get destroyed
现在就让他们的狗屎被摧毁吧
Manager Luo, you said me.
洛经理，你说的是我。
The main thing is,
最主要的是，
i...
我...
It's not good if I have stomach problems.
如果我有胃病那就不好了。
Must be loud at a time like this.
这种时候一定要大声。
The main thing is,
最主要的是，
very disappointing.
非常失望。
Large horse spoon.
大马勺。
Chen Jia Ping
Chen Jia Ping
this time you definitely can't avoid it anymore
这一次你绝对不能再回避了
why am I avoiding it?
我为什么要避免它？
I do not do anything
我什么都不做
You've even taken off your clothes,
你连衣服都脱了
still said he didn't do anything.
仍然说他什么也没做。
Didn't I tell you?
我没告诉过你吗？
I just tried on a sweater
我刚刚试穿了一件毛衣
Lu Fangfang was kind enough to try on the sweater for me.
卢芳芳好心地帮我试穿这件毛衣。
I tried a sweater.
我尝试了一件毛衣。
Composing.
构成。
Continue your essay.
继续你的论文。
What can I make?
我能做什么？
They all know
他们都知道
Lu Fang and I are innocent
我和吕芳都是无辜的
yesterday after we fought
昨天我们吵架之后
I took back all the letters I wrote to you
我收回了所有写给你的信
I really want to burn it all down.
我真想把这一切都烧掉。
This is my fault.
这是我的错。
I'm not willing.
我不甘心。
However, inside it all are our beautiful memories.
然而，里面却全是我们美好的回忆。
So today I looked for you,
所以今天我来找你，
because I still hope in you.
因为我仍然对你抱有希望。
But you?
但是你？
In the woman's office
在女人的办公室里
still dare to undress
还敢脱衣服
instead of me telling you,
而不是我告诉你，
I took off my clothes just to try on a sweater.
我脱掉衣服只是为了试穿一件毛衣。
So what did he do
他做了什么
what did he touch
他碰了什么
You can't make other people look bad
你不能让别人难看
is that called touching it?
这也叫摸吗？
He hugged me from behind.
他从后面抱住了我。
Look at my waist and chest.
看看我的腰和胸。
Can you say all that?
你能说出这一切吗？
You're really great huh.
你真是太棒了呵呵。
These letters were returned by Chen Jiaping to Shuang Tao.
这些信是陈家平退回给双涛的。
I don't care.
我不在乎。
I'm telling you, Guoguo.
I'm telling you, Guoguo.
Today we both have agreed.
今天我们双方都同意了。
You should apologize to Lu Fang.
你应该向吕方道歉。
If you don't apologize
如果你不道歉
I can't work here anymore.
我不能再在这里工作了。
Do you know?
你知道吗？
You told him to get off.
你叫他下车。
Why did he come down?
他为什么下来？
You apologize to him,
你向他道歉，
why let it go down?
为什么让它下降？
On what basis should I apologize?
我应该在什么基础上道歉？
You scold him
你骂他
you're not sorry
你不后悔
so what am I doing wrong?
那么我做错了什么？
Fang, you go up.
芳，你上去吧。
I have to tell Shuang Tao to go apologize to you.
我得叫双桃去给你道歉。
Nona Zuo,
Nona Zuo,
you misunderstood.
你误会了。
I don't have any other meaning.
我没有任何其他意义。
Only
仅有的
only had eyes for Jia Ping.
眼里只有家平。
He usually pays attention to me too.
他平时也很关注我。
Like caring for each other between colleagues.
就像同事之间互相关心一样。
Try listening.
尝试倾听。
Try listening to what people are saying.
尝试听听人们在说什么。
You look again at how you behave.
你再看看自己的行为举止。
Guoguo, quickly apologize.
果果，赶紧道歉。
After apologizing,
道歉后，
let's just say our problem is solved.
就说我们的问题已经解决了。
Good.
好的。
I apologize
我道歉
Sorry, Fang.
对不起，方。
Indeed, you are better
确实，你更优秀
blame me
怪我
not guarding Jiaping well
没有好好守护家平
can you knit a sweater for him?
你能为他织一件毛衣吗？
And I
和我
I didn't even realise
我什至没有意识到
the weather is cold.
天气很冷。
He really needs a sweater.
他确实需要一件毛衣。
In the future
将来
you are beside him,
你在他身边，
I've calmed down.
我已经平静下来了。
Zuo twins, don't go too far.
左双胞胎，别走得太远。
Why are you getting emotional?
你为什么情绪激动？
Chen Jia Ping
Chen Jia Ping
if you act like this
如果你这样做
so start today
所以从今天开始
we just broke up.
我们刚刚分手。
Look at it.
看它。
If you break up, break up.
如果分手，就分手吧。
Can't you cheer up an angry girl?
你不能让一个生气的女孩开心起来吗？
I don't.
我不。
Persuade.
说服。
Yu.
于。
Go away.
离开。
Good.
好的。
Go!
去！
Luo Guanqun, are you really my big brother?
罗冠群，你真的是我大哥吗？
Guoguo, listen to my explanation.
果果，听我解释。
Listen to my explanation.
听听我的解释。
Correct.
正确的。
Arriving at Yu's house,
到了于家，
You also have to stay angry.
你还必须保持愤怒。
Understand?
理解？
What is our drama?
我们的戏剧是什么？
is it completely finished?
完全完成了吗？
We have been together for many years
我们已经在一起很多年了
broke up because of this.
因为这个分手了。
Your reasons are still not enough.
你的理由还不够充分。
But all this time we have to continue the cold war,
但一直以来我们不得不继续冷战，
don't meet.
不见面。
You shouldn't even come to the shop looking for me.
你甚至不应该来商店找我。
Besides, you don't want to see me at all.
再说了，你根本就不想见我。
You got into drama pretty quickly.
你很快就进入了戏剧界。
According to you,
照你说的，
Am I getting into a drama?
我这是进入话剧了吗？
The main thing is,
最主要的是，
I will find the right time
我会找到合适的时间
so that our relationship
以便我们的关系
in everyone's eyes,
在大家眼里，
there is a suitable ending.
有一个合适的结局。
So
所以
I haven't finished talking yet
我话还没说完
don't come with me.
别跟我来。
Are they actually serious or not?
他们到底是认真的还是不认真的？
There is right and there is wrong
有对也有错
section chief Chen
陈科长
where are you? I've been looking for you all day.
你在哪里？我一整天都在找你。
Look at it.
看它。
It's filled in.
已经填满了。
Entry time is 14:30
入场时间为14:30
Departure time is 15:10.
出发时间为15:10。
Fine, I understand.
好吧，我明白了。
I will speak later at the Military Police Headquarters.
稍后我将在宪兵总部发言。
You have to give it before noon.
你必须在中午之前给它。
Komandan Luo.
Komandan Luo.
I want to ask your permission.
我想请求你的许可。
Where is the left twin peach?
左边的双胞胎桃子在哪里？
Have you made up?
你和好了吗？
Make up what?
补什么？
It is estimated that this time,
估计这一次，
most likely will die.
很可能会死。
I'm here to ask permission.
我来这里是为了请求许可。
I have to go to the Military Police Headquarters.
我得去宪兵司令部。
To brand their swords.
为他们的剑打上烙印。
After stamping,
冲压后，
I'm just looking for my girlfriend again.
我只是再次寻找我的女朋友。
Good.
好的。
Hurry and go do your work.
赶紧去做你的工作吧。
Go, go.
走吧，走吧。
I go first.
我先走了。
Go away.
离开。